A six-year-old tips a pile of bricks onto the floor. A hundred shapes, a hundred
colors, no idea what to build. Twenty minutes later the booklet is upside-down, the
build has stalled, and the fun has turned into quiet frustration.
The problem is not the bricks. It is the paper manual. It cannot see what bricks are
on the floor, answer a question, or adapt when a child changes their mind.
Meet BrickBuddy. An AI building companion for six- to eight-year-olds. Show it the
pile, pick a build, then change colors, parts, and instructions by voice or tap — and
the manual stays in sync.
One simple path. Discover, inventory, build, learn, celebrate. Voice or a single tap
does the heavy lifting. Here is the live prototype, end to end.
The home screen gives the child one job: show Buddy the bricks.
Tap Let's Build, and the Discover screen opens.
There's one main action — scan my pile — and two secondary doors.
The product never asks a six-year-old to fill in a text box.
We'll tell Buddy out loud what we have.
A scanning sweep crosses the pile. One row at a time, the inventory pops in.
Sixty-seven bricks across nine shapes, with color and count surfaced like a receipt.
Three matched recommendations slide in — each citing the bricks the kid actually has.
We'll pick the Robot Dog.
Here is the core screen.
On the left, the 3D dog grows brick by brick.
On the right, a paper-textured manual.
The current step on one page, the running list of changes on the other.
Right now the build is red. Watch the manual when the child changes it.
The child says: make it blue.
The 3D dog changes first. Then the manual changes with it.
Step text. Piece counts. Color swatches.
On the right page, Buddy stamps the edit: red to blue.
That is the thing paper can never do.
Voice isn't all-or-nothing.
Make the head purple — and only the head changes.
Body, legs, and tail stay exactly as they were.
For precision, pointing is faster than talking.
Tap the orange button, pick a brick, choose a swatch.
BrickBuddy updates that single piece, and the manual logs the edit.
The same engine handles preset structural changes too.
Say: add wings.
BrickBuddy adds a final step to the manual, and the 3D model grows the new parts.
After building, the session pivots from making to learning.
BrickBuddy turns the model into a lesson — stability, levers, sound, symmetry, and measurement.
All tied to the pieces the child just placed.
A two-question quiz closes the learning stage.
Right answers unlock an achievement. Wrong answers bring a friendlier explanation.
Every session ends here.
Confetti, a rotating 3D trophy, a build report, and a printable certificate to put on the fridge.
Three things make this prototype practical. First, one shared engine keeps the model
and manual in sync. Second, brick data is declarative — inventory, steps, and
rendering all read from the same source. Third, it runs as a single web page on
Cloudflare's edge. No install, no app store, no sign-up.
BrickBuddy is a CMAA5043 final project by Yusong Huang and Jiayi Huang. Yusong led the
implementation: every screen, the 3D pipeline, the mutation engine, and the
deployment. Jiayi led the original concept, the user research with children, and the
demo materials.
The prototype is live on Cloudflare's edge. Scan the code, try it in any browser, and
come find us at the CMA exhibition. Thanks for watching.